<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no" ?>
<modDesc descVersion="107">
    <author>Ozz</author>
    <version>1.0.0.3</version>
    <iconFilename>icon_MoistureSystem.dds</iconFilename>
    <title>
        <en>Moisture System</en>
        <de>Feuchtigkeitssystem</de>
        <fr>Système D'Humidité</fr>
        <tr>Nem Sistemi</tr>
    </title>
    <description>
        <en><![CDATA[Moisture System

Transform your farming experience with a sophisticated moisture simulation system that brings realism and strategic depth to Farming Simulator 25. This comprehensive mod introduces dynamic moisture mechanics that fundamentally change how you approach crop management, harvest timing, and storage decisions.

Experience authentic environmental interactions where moisture levels fluctuate naturally across your farm based on terrain elevation, prevailing weather patterns (rainfall, snowfall, temperature fluctuations), and day/night cycles. Fields at lower elevations stay wetter while higher ground dries faster, so consider moisture levels when planning which crops to plant where and when to harvest. Every farming decision gains new weight as you balance optimal timing against changing conditions.

Advanced Crop Quality System: Your harvested yields are no longer uniform commodities. Each load receives a quality grade from A (premium) through D (poor) based on its moisture content at harvest, with direct economic consequences at the point of sale. Every crop species has been carefully calibrated with unique optimal moisture windows that reflect real-world agricultural standards. Master these ranges and time your operations precisely to maximize profitability. Access comprehensive grade tables and seasonal moisture projections through the integrated in-game interface (Shift+M).

Features:
- Terrain-aware field moisture simulation with monthly variation patterns across three distinct environment profiles (Dry/Wet/Normal)
- Sophisticated grass management system featuring progressive tedding mechanics, weather-responsive drying rates, and automatic hay conversion at optimal moisture thresholds. Multiple tedding passes accelerates drying if you need it.
- Ground rot: Grass and straw piles left exposed accumulate rain exposure over time, triggering progressive volume loss as organic material deteriorates. Timing your collection and baling operations becomes critical. Hay will revert to grass if it gets too wet.
- Bale rotting: Unprotected bales track cumulative rain exposure with initial tolerance periods, escalating decay rates based on exposure history, and limited recovery during dry spells. Strategic use of wrapping and shelter infrastructure protects your investment.
- Purchase the moisture meter hand tool in the store for precise field and pile readings on demand (You can display this in the HUD if preferred).

Extensive customization options allow you to calibrate moisture dynamics, tedding efficiency, decay parameters, and interface preferences to match your preferred gameplay experience. Whether you seek hardcore realism or a gentler introduction to moisture management, the system adapts to your vision.

Github: https://github.com/sprkem/FS25_MoistureSystem

Changelog:

1.0.0.4 [WIP]:
- Added assurance on moisture grid lookup
- Added Ukrainian translation thanks to sava4903-coder


1.0.0.3:
- Add safety check to prevent errors when using SIM Dashboard and using a harvester.

1.0.0.2:
- Rework events in multiplayer to reduce network traffic and subsequent issues.
- Fix an issue with rotting bales in object storages in multiplayer.
- Moisture and grade are now visible when harvesting on the fill HUD.
- Fix sporadic issue where crop would sell for a very low price
- Fix various other multiplayer issues
- Add safety check to avoid an issue loading a game when there is a bale in a baler
- Add Czech translation thanks to Kynuska
- Add Polish translation thanks to KITT3000

]]>
        </en>
        <de><![CDATA[Feuchtigkeitssystem

Transformieren Sie Ihr Farmerlebnis mit einem ausgefeilten Feuchtigkeitssimulationssystem, das Realismus und strategische Tiefe zu Farming Simulator 25 bringt. Dieses umfassende Mod führt dynamische Feuchtigkeitsmechaniken ein, die grundlegend ändern, wie Sie die Bewirtschaftung von Kulturen, Erntezeitpunkt und Lagerbeschaffenheit angehen.

Erleben Sie authentische Umweltinteraktionen, bei denen die Feuchtigkeitsstufen auf Ihrem Hof natürlich schwanken, basierend auf der Geländeerhebung, vorherrschenden Wettermuster (Niederschlag, Schneefall, Temperaturschwankungen) und Tag-Nacht-Zyklen. Felder in niedrigeren Höhenlagen bleiben feuchter, während höher gelegenes Land schneller austrocknet. Berücksichtigen Sie Feuchtigkeitswerte bei der Planung, welche Kulturen wo gepflanzt und wann geerntet werden sollen. Jede Entscheidung in der Landwirtschaft gewinnt neues Gewicht, während Sie das optimale Timing gegen die sich ändernden Bedingungen abwägen.

Fortgeschrittenes Kulturqualitätssystem: Ihre geernteten Erträge sind keine einheitlichen Rohstoffe mehr. Jede Ladung erhält basierend auf ihrem Feuchtigkeitsgehalt bei der Ernte eine Qualitätsbenotung von A (Premium) bis D (schlecht), mit direkten wirtschaftlichen Konsequenzen zum Zeitpunkt des Verkaufs. Jede Kulturart wurde sorgfältig mit einzigartigen optimalen Feuchtigkeitsfenstern kalibriert, die realen landwirtschaftlichen Standards entsprechen. Meistern Sie diese Bereiche und timen Sie Ihre Operationen präzise, um die Rentabilität zu maximieren. Greifen Sie auf umfassende Noten-Tabellen und saisonale Feuchtigkeitsprognosen über die integrierte In-Game-Schnittstelle (Shift+M) zu.

Funktionen:
- Geländebewusste Feldfeuchtesimulation mit monatlichen Variationsmustern über drei unterschiedliche Umgebungsprofile (Trocken/Nass/Normal)
- Ausgefeiltes Grasverwaltungssystem mit progressiver Wendelmechanik, wettereaktiven Trocknungsraten und automatischer Heuumwandlung bei optimalen Feuchtigkeitsschwellwerten. Mehrfaches Wenden beschleunigt das Trocknen, wenn Sie dies benötigen.
- Bodenverrottung: Gras- und Strohhaufen, die freigelegt bleiben, sammeln im Laufe der Zeit Regenerosion an und lösen fortschreitenden Volumenverlust aus, während organisches Material verfällt. Das richtige Timing von Sammel- und Ballenpressoperationen wird kritisch. Heu wird zu Gras, wenn es zu nass wird.
- Ballenverrottung: Ungeschützte Ballen verfolgen kumulative Regennässung mit anfänglichen Toleranzperioden, steigende Verfallsraten basierend auf Expositionshistorie und begrenzte Erholung während trockener Phasen. Strategische Verwendung von Wickelfolie und Schutzinfrastruktur schützt Ihre Investition.
- Kaufen Sie das mobile Feuchtemessgerät im Store für präzise Feld- und Haufen-Messungen auf Abruf (Sie können dies bei Bedarf im HUD anzeigen).

Umfangreiche Anpassungsoptionen ermöglichen es Ihnen, die Feuchtigkeitsdynamik, Wendeleffizienz, Verfallsparameter und Schnittstelleneinstellungen an Ihr bevorzugtes Spielerlebnis anzupassen. Ob Sie hartwöchige Realismus oder eine sanftere Einführung in die Feuchtigkeitsverwaltung bevorzugen – das System passt sich Ihrer Vision an.

Github: https://github.com/sprkem/FS25_MoistureSystem

Änderungsprotokoll:

1.0.0.2:
- Überarbeitung der Ereignisse im Multiplayer zur Reduzierung des Netzwerkverkehrs und daraus resultierender Probleme.
- Behebung eines Problems mit verrottenden Ballen in Objektlagern im Multiplayer.
- Feuchtigkeit und Qualitätsstufe sind jetzt beim Ernten im Füllstand-HUD sichtbar.
- Sporadisches Problem behoben, bei dem Ernte zu einem sehr niedrigen Preis verkauft wurde
- Verschiedene Multiplayer-Probleme behoben
- Sicherheitsprüfung hinzugefügt, um ein Problem beim Laden eines Spielstands zu vermeiden, wenn sich ein Ballen in einer Ballenpresse befindet
- Tschechische Übersetzung hinzugefügt, dank Kynuska
- Polnische Übersetzung hinzugefügt, dank KITT3000

]]>
        </de>
        <fr><![CDATA[Système D'Humidité

Transformez votre expérience agricole avec un système de simulation d'humidité sophistiqué qui apporte du réalisme et de la profondeur stratégique à Farming Simulator 25. Ce mod complet introduit une mécanique d'humidité dynamique qui change fondamentalement votre approche de la gestion des cultures, du timing de récolte et des décisions de stockage.

Découvrez des interactions environnementales authentiques où les niveaux d'humidité fluctuent naturellement sur votre ferme en fonction de l'élévation du terrain, des conditions météorologiques (pluie, neige, variations de température) et des cycles jour/nuit. Les champs en basse altitude restent plus humides tandis que les terres élevées sèchent plus rapidement. Tenez compte des niveaux d'humidité lorsque vous planifiez où planter vos cultures et quand les récolter. Chaque décision agricole prend du poids supplémentaire en équilibrant le timing optimal par rapport aux conditions changeantes.

Système avancé de qualité des cultures : Vos rendements récoltés ne sont plus des produits uniformes. Chaque chargement reçoit une note de qualité de A (premium) à D (faible) en fonction de sa teneur en humidité au moment de la récolte, avec des conséquences économiques directes au moment de la vente. Chaque espèce de culture a été soigneusement calibrée avec des fenêtres d'humidité optimales uniques qui reflètent les normes agricoles réelles. Maîtrisez ces plages et chronométrez vos opérations précisément pour maximiser la rentabilité. Accédez aux tables de notes complètes et aux projections d'humidité saisonnières via l'interface intégrée du jeu (Maj+M).

Caractéristiques :
- Simulation d'humidité des champs sensible au terrain avec modèles de variation mensuelle sur trois profils environnementaux distincts (Sec/Humide/Normal)
- Système de gestion des herbes sophistiqué avec mécanique de fanage progressive, taux de séchage réactifs aux intempéries et conversion automatique en foin aux seuils d'humidité optimaux. Plusieurs passages de fanage accélèrent le séchage si vous en avez besoin.
- Pourriture au sol : Les tas d'herbe et de paille laissés à découvert accumulent l'exposition à la pluie au fil du temps, déclenchant une perte de volume progressive à mesure que la matière organique se détériore. Synchroniser la collecte et les opérations de mise en balles devient critique. Le foin redevient de l'herbe s'il devient trop humide.
- Pourriture des balles : Les balles non protégées suivent l'exposition cumulative à la pluie avec les périodes de tolérance initiales, les taux de dégradation croissants en fonction de l'historique d'exposition, et une récupération limitée pendant les périodes sèches. L'utilisation stratégique de l'enrubannage et des infrastructures d'abri protège votre investissement.
- Achetez l'outil de mesure d'humidité à main dans le magasin pour des lectures précises des champs et des tas sur demande (Vous pouvez l'afficher dans l'HUD si vous préférez).

Les options de personnalisation étendues vous permettent de calibrer la dynamique d'humidité, l'efficacité du fanage, les paramètres de dégradation et les préférences d'interface pour correspondre à votre expérience de jeu préférée. Que vous cherchiez un réalisme hardcore ou une introduction plus douce à la gestion de l'humidité, le système s'adapte à votre vision.

Github: https://github.com/sprkem/FS25_MoistureSystem

Journal des modifications :

1.0.0.2 :
- Refonte des événements en multijoueur pour réduire le trafic réseau et les problèmes associés.
- Correction d'un problème avec les balles en décomposition dans les stockages d'objets en multijoueur.
- L'humidité et la qualité sont désormais visibles lors de la récolte sur le HUD de remplissage.
- Correction d'un problème sporadique où les récoltes se vendaient à un prix très bas
- Correction de divers problèmes multijoueur
- Ajout d'une vérification de sécurité pour éviter un problème de chargement de partie lorsqu'une balle se trouve dans une presse à balles
- Ajout de la traduction tchèque grâce à Kynuska
- Ajout de la traduction polonaise grâce à KITT3000

]]>
        </fr>
    </description>
    <extraSourceFiles>
        <sourceFile filename="src/data/CropValueMap.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/data/MoistureClamp.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/extensions/PlayerHUDUpdateExtension.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/extensions/PlaceableInfoTriggerExtension.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/extensions/CutterExtension.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/extensions/DischargeableExtension.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/extensions/CombineExtension.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/extensions/ForageWagonExtension.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/extensions/BalerExtension.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/extensions/BaleExtension.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/extensions/PlaceableObjectStorageExtension.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/extensions/FillVolumeExtension.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/extensions/MowerExtension.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/extensions/TedderExtension.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/extensions/WindrowerExtension.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/extensions/SellingStationExtension.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/extensions/LoadingStationExtension.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/gui/CropGradeTableRenderer.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/gui/MoistureGuiGrades.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/gui/MoistureGuiCalendar.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/gui/MoistureGui.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/GroundPropertyTracker.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/BaleRottingSystem.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/events/InitialClientStateEvent.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/events/MoistureSettingsEvent.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/events/MoistureUpdateEvent.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/events/PilePropertyRequestEvent.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/events/PilePropertyResponseEvent.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/events/ObjectMoistureRequestEvent.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/events/ObjectMoistureResponseEvent.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/events/BaleRottingRequestEvent.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/events/BaleRottingResponseEvent.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/MoistureSettings.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/handTools/MoistureMeterTool.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/main.lua"/>
    </extraSourceFiles>
    <multiplayer supported="true"/>
    <l10n filenamePrefix="languages/l10n" />

    <actions>
        <action name="MOISTURE_MENU" category="SYSTEM" axisType="HALF" ignoreComboMask="false" />
    </actions>

    <inputBinding>
        <actionBinding action="MOISTURE_MENU">
            <binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="KEY_lshift KEY_m" />
        </actionBinding>
    </inputBinding>
    
    <helpLines>
        <category title="$l10n_help_moisture_title">
            <page title="$l10n_help_moisture_overview_title" iconSliceId="helpline.icon_shop">
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_help_moisture_overview_1"/>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_help_moisture_overview_2"/>
                </paragraph>
            </page>
            <page title="$l10n_help_moisture_field_title" iconSliceId="helpline.farmingBasics_harvesting">
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_help_moisture_field_1"/>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_help_moisture_field_2"/>
                </paragraph>
            </page>
            <page title="$l10n_help_moisture_grading_title" iconSliceId="helpline.icon_yieldBoost">
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_help_moisture_grading_1"/>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_help_moisture_grading_2"/>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_help_moisture_grading_3"/>
                </paragraph>
            </page>
            <page title="$l10n_help_moisture_grass_title" iconSliceId="helpline.crops_grass">
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_help_moisture_grass_1"/>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_help_moisture_grass_2"/>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_help_moisture_grass_3"/>
                </paragraph>
            </page>
            <page title="$l10n_help_moisture_groundrot_title" iconSliceId="helpline.icon_greenery">
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_help_moisture_groundrot_1"/>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_help_moisture_groundrot_2"/>
                </paragraph>
            </page>
            <page title="$l10n_help_moisture_bales_title" iconSliceId="helpline.icon_others">
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_help_moisture_bales_1"/>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_help_moisture_bales_2"/>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_help_moisture_bales_3"/>
                </paragraph>
            </page>
            <page title="$l10n_help_moisture_meter_title" iconSliceId="helpline.firstSteps_startingEquipment">
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_help_moisture_meter_1"/>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_help_moisture_meter_2"/>
                </paragraph>
            </page>
            <page title="$l10n_help_moisture_settings_title" iconSliceId="helpline.firstSteps_whatFarmer">
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_help_moisture_settings_1"/>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_help_moisture_settings_2"/>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>
                    <text text="$l10n_help_moisture_settings_3"/>
                </paragraph>
            </page>
        </category>
    </helpLines>
    
    <storeItems>
        <storeItem xmlFilename="objects/moistureMeter/moistureMeter.xml"/>
    </storeItems>
</modDesc>